Ted Koppel Collection
Ted Koppel Collection
- The Koppel Report, 1988-1990
  - Sex in the Soviet Union, aired 12/19/1990
    - Katya interview Part 2/Beauty Roll Moscow University/Svetlana Vickers Interview Part 1 (Sex 22), 07/15/1990; Interview with Katya [Russian with English translation] Katya discusses the emergence of modeling in Soviet Russia, the treatment of women by men, and some of her ideological beliefs. Walking shots of Katya at Moscow University. Interview with Svetlana Vickers [Russian with English translation] Vickers discusses how the Soviet Union polices morality, an erotic art exhibit, and sex in Soviet Russia; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:48; koppel_00464 (Box 14)
    - Svetlana Vickers Interview Part 2/Katya Vickers interview (Sex 23)., 07/15/1990; Interview with Svetlana Vickers [Russian with English translation] S. Vickers discusses sexuality in the Soviet Union, pornography, ideological beliefs, and the treatment of women by men. Interview with Katya Vickers [Russian with English translation] K. Vickers discusses the communist youth league, where young people have sex, contraception, abortion, prostitution, and femininity.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:28:58; koppel_00465 (Box 14)
    - Paulik Statue/Party Beauty Roll/Party Interviews Part 1 (Sex 24)., 07/15/1990; Paulik figurine. Footage of young people at a party. Footage includes individuals smoking, drinking, conversing, listening to music, and dancing. Interview with individuals at party [primarily in Russian with some English] Individuals discuss sexuality in the Soviet Union, pornography, and the sexual revolution.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:01; koppel_00466 (Box 14)
    - Party Interviews Part 2 (Sex 25), 07/15/1990; Interviews with individuals at party [primarily in Russian with some English] Individuals discuss sex in the Soviet Union and related topics. Interview includes footage of a divorced couple talking about marriage in Soviet Russia; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:31:14; koppel_00467 (Box 14)
    - Larissa Remennick Beauty Roll (Sex 27), 07/16/1990; Footage of Larissa Remennick playing with her child at park and shopping at a drug store. Footage includes images of surrounding area and scenes from inside the drug store; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:22:37; koppel_00468 (Box 14)
    - Eugenia Debryanskaya Interview (Sex 28), 07/16/1990; Interview with Eugenia Debryanskaya, member of the radical party [Russian with English translation] Debryanskaya discusses sexual aspects of the party's platform, the formation of the party, the sexual minority, AIDS, the persecution of homosexuals, sexuality, and politics in the Soviet Union.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:27:12; koppel_00469 (Box 14)
    - Beer Hall Beauty Roll/Beer Hall Interview (Sex 29), 07/16/1990; Interior footage of a beer hall. Footage includes scenes of live music, drinking, smoking, eating, and people conversing. Interview with group of individuals at the beer hall [Russian with English translation] Individuals discuss dating, sex, pornography, and morality. Couple at the table talks about not wanting to marry despite being together for two years and the issues associated with having children in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:27:44; koppel_00470 (Box 14)
    - Kiev Train Station Beauty Roll (Sex 30), 07/16/1990; Interior footage of a train station in Kiev. Footage includes scenes of people waiting, an individual selling erotica, and people walking; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:19:36; koppel_00471 (Box 14)
    - Exterior Footage of Building/Piquant Show's Joy of Eros Rehearsals (Sex 31), 07/17/1990; Exterior footage of buildings from a high vantage point at sundown. Footage of cast before rehearsal. Rehearsal of Joy of Eros, including scenes of topless dancers; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:23; koppel_00472 (Box 14)
    - Joy of Eros Group Interview (Sex 32), 07/17/1990; Group interview with the Director, Choreographer, and dancers of the Joy of Eros [Russian with English translation] Piquant Show troupe. Troupe discusses the dance company, the meaning of the pieces rehearsed, sex in the Soviet Union, the differences between art and pornography, their feelings about performing in the nude, and sexual revolution; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:23; koppel_00473 (Box 14)
    - Joy of Eros Rehearsal/Exterior Footage of the Pravda Cultural Center/Metal Corrosion Beauty Roll (Sex 33), 07/17/1990; Dancers rehearsing the Joy of Eros. Exterior footage of the Pravda Cultural Center. Scenes of individuals drinking and smoking in a room. Footage of a band, Metal Corrosion, practicing. Group of females in lingerie enter room and start drinking, striping, and dancing to the band; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:31:14; koppel_00474 (Box 14)
    - Partying/Metal Corrosion Interview (Sex 34), 07/17/1990; Scenes of individuals drinking, smoking, and partying. Interview with Metal Corrosion band members with topless women in the background [Russian with English translation] Band members discuss the formation of Metal Corrosion, the use of erotic elements in their performances, and their political ideology; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:17:54; koppel_00475 (Box 14)
    - Spycam/Prostitutes (Sex 36), 07/17/1990; Hidden camera footage of a Russian hotel. Camera crew appears to be capturing footage of individuals picking up prostitutes; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:20:19; koppel_00476 (Box 14)
    - Birthing and Abortion Hospital Part 1/Hospital Interview (Sex 37)., 07/17/1990; Interior footage of a birthing and abortion hospital. Scenes of nurses conducting a meeting. Footage of a woman giving birth. Interview with a women inside the hospital [in Russian with some English] Footage of an abortion; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:25:47; koppel_00477 (Box 14)
    - Doctor Interview/Maternity Ward Interview/Birthing and Abortion Hospital Part 2 (Sex 38), 07/18/1990; Interview with a doctor inside a maternity hospital [Russian with English translation] Doctor discusses surgical abortions, the use of anesthesia, the economic condition of maternity hospitals, and the progress of Soviet hospitals during his career. Interview with woman in maternity ward [Russian with English translation] Woman discusses giving birth, the absence of her husband while giving birth, and abortions in the Soviet Union. Footage of newborns.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:24; koppel_00478 (Box 14)
    - Sasha Borodulin Interview Part 1 (Sex 39), 07/18/1990; Footage of individuals at the beach. Interview with photographer Sasha Borodulin [in English] Borodulin discusses the controversy of Playboy in the Soviet Union, the use of political symbols in his photography, the sexual revolution, privacy, and morality in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:28; koppel_00479 (Box 14)
    - Sasha Borodulin Interview Part 2/Photo Shoot Beauty Roll (Sex 40)., 07/18/1990; Interview with photographer Sasha Borodulin [in English] Borodulin briefly discusses the history of sex in the Soviet Union, how younger generations view sex, and his experiences working with Playboy. Beauty roll of Borodulin photo shoot.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:18:03; koppel_00480 (Box 14)
    - Igor Kon Interview Part 1 (Sex 41), 07/18/1990; Interview with Dr. Igor Kon [in English and Russian with English translation] Kon discusses the sexual history of Russia, Vladimir Lenin's perceptions of sexuality, the relationship between political repression and sexual repression, the state's control on sexual culture, and the lack of sex education in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:46; koppel_00481 (Box 14)
    - Igor Kon Interview Part 2 (Sex 42), 07/18/1990; Interview with Dr. Igor Kon [in English and Russian with English translation] Kon discusses the general understanding of sexology in the Soviet Union, Playboy, the film "Little Vera," homosexuality, laws pertaining to homosexuality, privacy, and the culture of sexuality in the Soviet Union.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:31:15; koppel_00482 (Box 14)
    - Igor Kon Interview Part 3 (Sex 43), 07/18/1990; Interview with Dr. Igor Kon [in English and Russian with English translation] Kon discusses the conservative strategy for demonizing sexual liberation, marital rape, sexual subcultures, sex education, sexual revolution, and the moral panic that is taking place in Soviet society.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:24:46; koppel_00483 (Box 14)
    - Andrei Shipilov Interview (Sex 44), 07/19/1990; Interview with Andrei Shipilov, the Director of Gosteleradio Youth Department [in English] Shipilov discusses topics related to sex in the Soviet Union, the relationship between politics and sex, the country's lack of condoms, sex education, and guidelines for displaying appropriate content on Soviet television. Footage of Shipilov standing and watching a Soviet television program; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:26:31; koppel_00484 (Box 14)
    - Juvan Shaestalov Interview Part 1 (Sex 45), 07/20/1990; Interview with Juvan Shaestalov, Secretary of Leningrad Writers Union [Russian with English translation] Shaestalov, a conservative poet, discusses the impact of the 1917 Revolution, the breakdown of traditional values in the Soviet Union, sexual revolution, Glasnost, and the influence of western culture on Soviet morality; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:26; koppel_00485 (Box 14)
    - Juvan Shaestalov Interview Part 2 (Sex 46), 07/20/1990; Interview with Juvan Shaestalov, Secretary of Leningrad Writers Union [Russian with English translation] Shaestalov, a conservative poet, discusses his opinion on Mikhail Gorbachev, Glasnost, the difference between traditional literature and modern eroticism, the Soviet edition of Playboy, and the influence of western culture on the sexualization of the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:13; koppel_00486 (Box 14)
    - Juvan Shaestalov Poem/Juvan Shaestalov Set Up Shots/Sergei Golog Interview Part 1 (Sex 47), 07/20/1990; Juvan Shaestalov reciting a poem [Russian with Engilsh translation] Set up shots of Shaestalov. Footage includes Shaestalov working at a desk in his apartment, walking through a courtyard, and entering a building. Interview with Sergei Golog, a Leningrad prostitution researcher [Russian with English translation] Golog discusses a variety of topics related to prostitution in the Soviet Union. Topics include the number of prostitutes in the Soviet Union, the government's definition of prostitution, and the different types of prostitution.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:13; koppel_00487 (Box 14)
    - Sergei Golog Interview Part 2/Sergei Golog Set Up Shots/Preacher at Kazan Cathedral with Christian Singers Part 1 (Sex 48), 07/20/1990; Interview with Sergei Golog, a Leningrad prostitution researcher [Russian with English translation] Golog discusses the differences between erotic films and sexual films, the average age of prostitutes, sexuality in the Soviet Union, and the Soviet edition of Playboy. Set up shots of Golog. Footage includes Shaestalov working in an office and walking through the streets. Drunk couple kissing in the street. Individual preaching to a crowd of people in front of the Kazan Cathedral. Christian singers; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:21; koppel_00488 (Box 14)
    - Preacher at Kazan Cathedral with Christian Singers Part 2/Prostitutes Outside Leningrad Hotel/Dimitri Shalin Interview Part 1 (Sex 49), 07/20/1990; Individual preaching to a crowd of people in front of the Kazan Cathedral. Christian singers. Individual playing guitar and singing with friends next to the preacher. Footage of prostitutes outside a Leningrad hotel. Interview with Dimitri Shalin [in English] Shalin discusses sex in the Soviet Union, the relationship between sex and politics, abortion, contraception, prostitution, privacy, and the sexual revolution; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:59; koppel_00489 (Box 15)
    - Dimitri Shalin interview Part 2/Dimitri Shalin Set Up Shots/Park Beauty Roll/Erotic Posters (Sex 50), 07/21/1990; Interview with Dimitri Shalin [in English] Shalin discusses sex and politics, glasnost, homosexuality, sex education, contraception, and his current role in helping establish sex education centers in the Soviet Union. Set up shots of Shalin walking through a park (multiple takes). Park Beauty Roll, includes footage of sculptures, foliage, and people walking. Footage of erotic posters on a busy Leningrad street; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:26:48; koppel_00490 (Box 15)
    - Georgiy Gurianov Interview/Gurianov Painting (Sex 51), 07/21/1990; Interview with gay artist Georgiy Gurianov [Russian with English translation] Gurianov discusses life as a gay artist in the Soviet Union, the acceptance of homosexuality in Leningrad, and art in the Soviet Union. Footage of Gurianov painting in his studio; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:54; koppel_00491 (Box 15)
    - Timur Novikov Interview (Sex 52), 07/21/1990; Interview with gay artist Timur Novikov [Russian with English translation] Novikov discusses life as a gay artist in the Soviet Union, the sexual revolution in relation to art and culture, AIDS, glasnost, and morality in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:30; koppel_00492 (Box 15)
    - Timur Novikov Set Up Shots/Fortress Beach/Drunk Couple in Park (Sex 53), 07/21/1990; Set up shots of Timur Navikov. Footage includes Navikov walking through his studio, entering a "boys club," and walking across a bridge (multiple takes). Beauty roll of young people at Fortress Beach in Leningrad. Footage includes shots of the water, the surrounding area, couples laying out, and people playing volleyball. Beauty roll of drunk couple in the park. Footage includes scenes of the couple stumbling, holding hands, walking, and shots of the surrounding area.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:27:34; koppel_00493 (Box 15)
    - Gay Men in Catherine Gardens/Gay Men Meeting in Front of a Department Store (Sex 54), 07/21/1990; Beauty roll of Catherine Gardens, Leningrad. Footage includes people playing chess, individuals walking, and gay men hanging out on park benches. Footage of gay men meeting in front of an old department store; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:10:46; koppel_00494 (Box 15)
    - Individual Selling Erotic Newspapers/Katya Burova Interview Part 1 (Sex 55), 07/22/1990; Footage of individual selling erotic newspapers. Individual making a speech to an assembled crowd [in Russian] Footage of a cafeteria. Ted Koppel interviews Katya Burova in Gorky Park [Russian with English translation] Burova discusses Gorky Park, contraception, abortion, the treatment of abortion patients, morality, and where young people have sex; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:12; koppel_00495 (Box 15)
    - Katya Burova Interview Part 2 (Sex 56), 07/22/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Katya Burova in Gorky Park [Russian with English translation] Burova discusses privacy, marriage and divorce, morality in the Soviet Union, and sexuality. Footage of Koppel and Burova talking after the interview; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:19:14; koppel_00496 (Box 15)
    - Gorky Park Beauty Roll (Sex 57), 07/22/1990; Beauty roll of Gorky Park. Footage includes scenes of couples paddle boating and a Soviet disco. Young people dancing to American music. Katya Burova dancing with a friend.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:16:45; koppel_00497 (Box 15)
    - Nina Kirillova Interview Part 1 (Sex 58), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Nina Kirillova during lunch [Russian with English translation] Koppel, Kirillova, and crew eating lunch at Kirillova's apartment. Kirillova discusses life in the Soviet Union, the cost of living, her income, government corruption, and why taxi drivers make more money than government workers; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:24; koppel_00498 (Box 15)
    - Nina Kirillova Interview Part 2 (Sex 59), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Nina Kirillova [Russian with English translation] Kirillova discusses Soviet politics, the possibility of change in the Soviet Union, the basis for Soviet morality, dissent against the government, glasnost, and the KGB; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:50; koppel_00499 (Box 15)
    - Nina Kirillova Interview Part 3 (Sex 60), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Nina Kirillova [Russian with English translation] Kirillova discusses marrying her husband for protection, divorce, alcoholism in the Soviet Union, the treatment of women by men, love and sex, privacy, and contraception.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:31:14; koppel_00500 (Box 15)
    - Julia Kirillova Interview/Ted Koppel Bathroom Stand Up (Sex 61)., 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel talking with Nina Kirillova in kitchen [in German] Footage of Kirillova's kitchen. Ted Koppel interviews Julia Kirillova, the daughter of Nina Kirillova [Russian with English translation] J. Kirillova discusses the lack of sex education in school and her knowledge of contraception. Ted Koppel stand up in Nina Kirillova's bathroom (multiple takes). Stand up discusses the living arrangements of divorced couples in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:19:37; koppel_00501 (Box 15)
    - Sergei Trotsky Interview Part 1 (Sex 62), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Metal Corrosion member Sergei Trotsky [Russian with English translation] Trotsky discusses the formation of Metal Corrosion, the band's political message, AIDS, the lack of condoms, the rational behind nudity in their performances, and sex in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:31:18; koppel_00502 (Box 15)
    - Sergei Trotsky Interview Part 2 (Sex 63), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews Metal Corrosion member Sergei Trotsky [Russian with English translation] Trotsky and Metal Corrosion members discuss morality, lyrics, the success of their band, and being arrested during one of their performances; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:17:32; koppel_00503 (Box 15)
    - Metal Corrosion and their Entourage/Madam Interview Part 1 (Sex 64)., 07/23/1990; Footage of Metal Corrosion and their entourage smoking, drinking, and hanging out inside their practice space. Exterior footage of Metal Corrosion's practice space. Ted Koppel interviews a Soviet Madam [Russian with English translation] The Madam discusses the differences between western prostitution and Soviet prostitution, the use of alcohol by prostitutes, hard currency prostitution, hostesses, and the rationale behind women getting involved in prostitution; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:28:00; koppel_00504 (Box 15)
    - Madam Interview Part 2 (Sex 65), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews a Soviet Madam [Russian with English translation] The Madam discusses how she finds and controls her prostitutes, the business side of prostitution, the level of sex education prostitutes have, contraception, the film "Little Vera," and homosexuality; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:27:55; koppel_00505 (Box 15)
    - Madam Interview Part 3 (Sex 66), 07/23/1990; Ted Koppel interviews a Soviet Madam [Russian with English translation] The Madam discusses how she got involved in prostitution, her current role in prostitution, hostesses, and morality in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:22:45; koppel_00506 (Box 15)
    - Mezh Hotel Bribe with Tamara/Sasha Borodulin in Restaurant (Sex 67)., 07/22/1990; Footage of hotel worker denying Tamara access into a restaurant. Hotel worker tells crew members that the hotel does not allow guests to have visitors. Woman urges camera crew to leave so she can bribe the worker into allowing Tamara into the restaurant. The reason Tamara could not get into the hotel was because she was profiled as a potential prostitute. Tamara meets Sasha Borodulin in restaurant and they briefly discuss the encounter; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:10:20; koppel_00507 (Box 15)
    - Valentina Popova Interview (Sex 68), 07/23/1990; Interview with Dr. Valentina Popova, the Director of House of Sexuality and Culture [Russian with English translation] Dr. Popova discusses the mission of the House of Sexuality and Culture, the most common problems she sees, western influence on sexuality, morality in the Soviet Union, sex education, and issues currently facing Soviet youth; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:57; koppel_00508 (Box 15)
    - Sex Education Beauty Roll/Valentina Popova Teaching/Sasha Alexandra Interview Part 1 (Sex 69), 07/24/1990; Beauty roll of a sex education class for kids. Footage includes the students watching a slide show and listening to a lecture. Set up shots of Dr. Valentina Popova teaching a class of children. Popova talking to Sasha Alexandra [in Russian] Interview with Sasha Alexandra [Russian with English translation] Alexandra discusses her experiences with being pregnant, abortion, lack of a formal sex education, and life as a Soviet teenager; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:30:19; koppel_00509 (Box 15)
    - Sasha Alexandra Interview Part 2/Valentina Popova Interview/Sasha Borodulin Model Audition Part 1/Sasha Borodulin Interview (Sex 70)., 07/24/1990; Interview with Sasha Alexandra [Russian with English translation] Alexandra discusses prostitution and values. Interview with Valentina Popova [Russian with English translation] Popova discusses issues related to Alexandra. Sasha Borodulin auditioning models. Footage includes a series of models walking across a stage and taking direction from Borodulin. Ted Koppel briefly interviews Sasha Borodulin [in English] Borodulin discusses the purpose of the audition and the models' ambition to work abroad.; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:28:02; koppel_00510 (Box 15)
    - Sasha Borodulin Model Audition Part 2/Interview with Model and her Father (Sex 71), 07/24/1990; Sasha Borodulin talking with a model and her father [in Russian] Ted Koppel interviews the model and father [Russian with English translation] They discuss her desire to become a professional model, the possibility of moving abroad, and morality; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:29:12; koppel_00511 (Box 15)
    - Model Audition Interviews (Sex 72), 07/24/1990; Ted Koppel interviews models at the Sasha Borodulin audition. Models discuss their experiences, how they found out about the audition, the possibility of working in France, and the correlation between modeling and prostitution in the Soviet Union; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:17:37; koppel_00512 (Box 15)
    - Tolga Monastery Church Service (Sex 73), 07/25/1990; Exterior footage of Tolga Monastery. Footage of a church service from inside and outside of the monastery; Videotape, Betacam SP, original footage, 0:25:25; koppel_00513 (Box 15)